A Guide to the Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files, 1994-1995
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
Papers of the President of the University of Virginia, Office Administrative Files 1994-1995
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
RG-2/1/2.971
This collection consists of 22,000 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Access restrictions may apply to specific student records under the terms of the Family Educational Rights and Privacy Act (F.E.R.P.A.).
Acquisition Information
This collection was forwarded on 1998 January 21.
Scope and Content Information
These files constitute the major record series generated by John Thomas Casteen, the president of the University of Virginia. The records consist chiefly of correspondence, but also include reports, minutes, clippings, memoranda, and related papers concerning all areas of business of the president's office.
Organization
SERIES I: General Files, 1994-1995 Boxes 1-42
SERIES II: Restricted Files, 1994-1995 Boxes 43-44
Contents List
- SERIES I: General Files
  - "A-Al" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - "Am" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - "An-Az" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 1)
  - Admissions--General 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Law 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Admissions--Medical 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - African-American Affairs (General) 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - African-American Affairs--Woodson Inst. 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Alumni--General (1-2 of 4) 1994-1995 (Box 2)
  - Alumni--General (3-4 of 4) 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - American Association of State Colleges 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - American Council of Education (3 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 3)
  - Anthropology 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Applications for Positions (2 folders) (Restricted) 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Architecture 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Art--General 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Art--Bayly Museum 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Assessment, Planning and Studies 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Associated Western University 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Colleges--General 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities (1-3 of 4) 1994-1995 (Box 4)
  - Association of American Universities (4 of 4) 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Association of American Universities--General (3 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Association of Governing Boards (1-2 of 3) 1994-1995 (Box 5)
  - Association of Governing Boards (3 of 3) 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Association of Governing Boards Advisory Council of President 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Association of Virginia Colleges 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Astronomy--General 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Athletics (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--ACC (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--CFA 1994-1995 (Box 6)
  - Athletics--NCAA (3 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - Attorney General (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - Auditor-Internal--General 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - Auditor of Public Accounts 1994-1995 (Box 7)
  - "Ba-Bm" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - "Bn-Br" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - "Bs-Bz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 8)
  - Business and Finance--General (4 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - "Ca-Cg" Miscellaneous (1 of 4) 1994-1995 (Box 9)
  - "Ca-Cg" Miscellaneous (2-4 of 4) 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - "Ch-Cn" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - "Co-Cz" Miscellaneous (1-2 of 5) 1994-1995 (Box 10)
  - "Co-Cz" Miscellaneous (3-5 of 5) 1994-1995 (Box 11)
  - Carr's Hill--General (1-2 of 3) 1994-1995 (Box 11)
  - Carr's Hill--General (3 of 3) 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - Casteen 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - Cavalier Daily 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - Center for Innovative Technology 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - City of Charlottesville--General 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - Charlottesville, City of Planning and Coordination 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - Chemistry 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - Clinch Valley College (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - College of Arts and Sciences 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - College Board (1 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 12)
  - College Board (2 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 13)
  - Commerce--General 1994-1995 (Box 13)
  - Community Colleges 1994-1995 (Box 13)
  - Comptroller 1994-1995 (Box 13)
  - Condolences "A-Z" (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 13)
  - Congress--General 1994-1995 (Box 13)
  - Connie Lee 1994-1995 (Box 13)
  - Continuing Education 1994-1995 (Box 13)
  - Council of Presidents (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 14)
  - "Da-De" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 14)
  - "Df-Dz" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 14)
  - Darden--General 1994-1995 (Box 14)
  - Dean's Meetings 1994-1995 (Box 14)
  - Dedication of New Buildings 1994-1995 (Box 14)
  - Development (1 of 6) 1994-1995 (Box 14)
  - Development (2-6 of 6) 1994-1995 (Box 15)
  - Drama 1994-1995 (Box 15)
  - "E" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Education--General 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Engineering and Applied Science 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - English--General 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Enrollment--General 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Enrollment--Statistics 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Environmental Sciences--General 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - Equal Opportunity Employers (3 folders) (Restricted) 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - "Fa-Fh" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - "Fi-Fz" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 16)
  - "Fi-Fz" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - Facilities Management 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - Faculty 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - Faculty--Arts and Sciences 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - Family Violence Prevention Fund 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - Financial Aid to Students 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - Food Services (ARA) 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - French Language and Literature 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - "Ga-Gn" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 17)
  - "Go-Gz" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 18)
  - General Assembly (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 18)
  - General Assembly-Legislative Summaries 1994-1995 (Box 18)
  - General Assembly-House Appropriations 1994-1995 (Box 18)
  - General Assembly-Senate Finance 1994-1995 (Box 18)
  - General Counsel (1-2 of 3) 1994-1995 (Box 18)
  - General Counsel (3 of 3) 1994-1995 (Box 19)
  - General Services (state) 1994-1995 (Box 19)
  - Gifts and Grants (A-C)-- (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 19)
  - Gifts and Grants (D-F) 1994-1995 (Box 19)
  - Gifts and Grants (G-K) (1 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 19)
  - Gifts and Grants (G-K) (2 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 20)
  - Gifts and Grants (L-P) 1994-1995 (Box 20)
  - Gifts and Grants (Q-S) 1994-1995 (Box 20)
  - Gifts and Grants (T-Z) 1994-1995 (Box 20)
  - Government and Foreign Affairs 1994-1995 (Box 20)
  - Governmental and Community Relations 1994-1995 (Box 20)
  - Governors Office--General (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 21)
  - Governors Office-Administration 1994-1995 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Office--Education 1994-1995 (Box 21)
  - Governors Office-Finance 1994-1995 (Box 21)
  - Governor's Public Safety and Transportation 1994-1995 (Box 21)
  - Graduate School of Arts and Sciences 1994-1995 (Box 21)
  - "Ha-Hh" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 21)
  - "Hi-Hz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 22)
  - History--General 1994-1995 (Box 22)
  - Honor System (Restricted) 1994-1995 (Box 22)
  - Housing--General 1994-1995 (Box 22)
  - Human Resources, Department of 1994-1995 (Box 22)
  - "I" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 22)
  - "I" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 23)
  - Information Technology (state) 1994-1995 (Box 23)
  - Information, Technology of Community 1994-1995 (Box 23)
  - International Students--General 1994-1995 (Box 23)
  - International Studies--General 1994-1995 (Box 23)
  - "J" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 23)
  - Jefferson, Thomas Memorial Found. 1994-1995 (Box 23)
  - Jefferson Scholars 1994-1995 (Box 24)
  - Jeffersonian Restoration Design Committee 1994-1995 (Box 24)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review 1994-1995 (Box 24)
  - "K" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 24)
  - "L" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 24)
  - Law--General 1994-1995 (Box 25)
  - Lawn Policy Use 1994-1995 (Box 25)
  - Library--General 1994-1995 (Box 25)
  - "Ma-Me" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 25)
  - "Mc" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 25)
  - "Mf-Mz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 26)
  - Major Events 1994-1995 (Box 26)
  - Management and Budget (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 26)
  - Marine Science 1994-1995 (Box 26)
  - Marines Museum--General (1-2 of 3) 1994-1995 (Box 26)
  - Marines Museum--General (3 of 3) 1994-1995 (Box 27)
  - Materials Management--Purchasing 1994-1995 (Box 27)
  - Medical Center--General (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 27)
  - Medical Center-Health Sciences Council 1994-1995 (Box 27)
  - Medical Center--Medical School 1994-1995 (Box 27)
  - Medical Center-Hospital 1994-1995 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center-Professional 1994-1995 (Box 28)
  - Medical Center-Nursing 1994-1995 (Box 28)
  - Music--General 1994-1995 (Box 28)
  - "N" Miscellaneous (3 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 28)
  - "Nb-Nz" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 29)
  - National Association of State University and Land Grant (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 29)
  - NASULGC--Board on Oceans and Atmosphere 1994-1995 (Box 29)
  - National Science Foundation 1994-1995 (Box 29)
  - Nellie Mae--General (1-2 of 3) 1994-1995 (Box 29)
  - Nellie Mae--General (3 of 3) 1994-1995 (Box 30)
  - Newcomb Hall (Restricted) 1994-1995 (Box 30)
  - "O" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 30)
  - Oak Ridge Associated University--General 1994-1995 (Box 30)
  - "Pa-Ph" Miscellaneous (1 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 30)
  - "Pa-Ph" Miscellaneous (2 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - "Pi-Pz" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - Parking and Transportation (State) 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - Parking and Transportation 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - Personnel and Training (State) 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - Planning--General. 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - Planning and Budget-state (1 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 31)
  - Planning and Budget-state (2 of 2) 1994-1995 (Box 32)
  - President's Senior Cabinet Meetings (2folders) 1994-1995 (Box 32)
  - Promotions and Tenure--General 1994-1995 (Box 32)
  - Provost 1994-1995 (Box 32)
  - Provost--Associate Provost for Research 1994-1995 (Box 32)
  - Psychology--General 1994-1995 (Box 32)
  - "Q" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 32)
  - "Ra-Rh" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 33)
  - "Ri-Rz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 33)
  - Recommendations (3 folders) (Restricted) 1994-1995 (Box 33)
  - ROTC 1994-1995 (Box 33)
  - ROTC--Air Force 1994-1995 (Box 33)
  - ROTC--Army 1994-1995 (Box 33)
  - ROTC--Navy 1994-1995 (Box 34)
  - Rotunda Society 1994-1995 (Box 34)
  - "Sa-Sh" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 34)
  - "Si-Sn" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 34)
  - "So" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 35)
  - "Sp-Sz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 35)
  - Salaries 1994-1995 (Box 35)
  - Senate--University 1994-1995 (Box 35)
  - Sociology 1994-1995 (Box 36)
  - Southern Association of Colleges (5 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 36)
  - Southern Regional Education Board 1994-1995 (Box 36)
  - Sponsored Programs 1994-1995 (Box 36)
  - SCHEV (3 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 37)
  - SCHEV--Council Notes 1994-1995 (Box 37)
  - State Department of Education--General 1994-1995 (Box 37)
  - Student Affairs--General 1994-1995 (Box 38)
  - Student Affairs--Fraternity/Sorority 1994-1995 (Box 38)
  - Student Council--General 1994-1995 (Box 38)
  - Student Council--Minutes 1994-1995 (Box 38)
  - Summer Session 1994-1995 (Box 38)
  - "Ta-Te" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 38)
  - "Tf-Tz" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 38)
  - "U" Miscellaneous (4 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 39)
  - United Way--Combine Charitable 1994-1995 (Box 39)
  - University Journal 1994-1995 (Box 40)
  - University Research Association--General 1994-1995 (Box 40)
  - University Guides--General 1994-1995 (Box 40)
  - University Police--General 1994-1995 (Box 40)
  - University Policy 1994-1995 (Box 40)
  - University Press of Virginia 1994-1995 (Box 40)
  - University Relations/News Office (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 40)
  - University Union 1994-1995 (Box 40)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (1-2 of 5) 1994-1995 (Box 40)
  - "V" Miscellaneous (3-5 of 5) 1994-1995 (Box 41)
  - Virginia Academy of Science 1994-1995 (Box 41)
  - Virginia Festival of American Film 1994-1995 (Box 41)
  - Virginia Quarterly Review 1994-1995 (Box 41)
  - Virginia Student Aid Foundation 1994-1995 (Box 41)
  - "Wa-Wh" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 42)
  - "Wi-Wz" Miscellaneous (2 folders) 1994-1995 (Box 42)
  - Weldon Cooper Center for Public Service 1994-1995 (Box 42)
  - "X, Y, Z" Miscellaneous 1994-1995 (Box 42)
- SERIES II: Restricted Files (Box 43-44)